# Rhydian Jenkins

- in LinkedIn.com/in/rhydian-jenkins-30309085
- GitHub.com/RhydianJenkins
- **\** 07384 629 336
- Rhydz@msn.com
- **♀** SA11 2LS

## Personal Profile

Committed and driven Computer Science PhD graduate with an understanding of a variety of software and computing aspects. Experienced with working in groups and alone using a wide range of technologies including modern TypeScript and JavaScript (Vue, Next, and Svelte), MVC Frameworks (Symfony/Zend/Laminas), Docker, and Java applications.

Passionate about learning, and familiar working in Windows and Linux environments, Containers, Virtual Machines and shells. Strives for a principle first approach when learning, combined with a passion to engage in any challenge with a 'can-do' attitude.

## Skills

- Infrastructure and DevOps (Docker, Kubernetes, Git, GCP)
- Front end Vue, React, Svelte(Kit), Next, Nuxt, Vite
- Back end Symfony/Zend/Laminas MVC
- Package managment and build tools (npm, Composer, Docker-compose, Maven, Make, ...)
- Public speaking while presenting work at various conferences

## Experience

#### BaseKit

Apr 2022–present

#### Full Stack Developer

Worked on a large DIY eCommerce site builder for individual and white label customers. Responsible for maintaining large legacy systems as well as developing new features with the latest standards.

#### Responsibilities:

- Front end development with React TS
- Back end development with Symfony Micro PHP

#### WCBS

 $\begin{array}{c} \text{Jan 2021-Apr} \\ \text{2022} \end{array}$ 

## Full Stack Developer

Part of an agile team working remotely to develop a modern cloud native Management Information System (MIS) solution for a number of schools, delivering frequent (2x weekly) releases on high standard product requirements. Operated using a broad tech stack, including Vue2 and Vue3, Symfony, Redis, Kubernetes, Docker, and GitHub.

#### Responsibilities:

- Develop a Vue.js app in the TypeScript and JavaScript
- Develop a RESTful API in Symfony
- Ensuring code quality through Jest/PHPUnit tests and code review
- Deploying releases through the various environments
- CI/CD through GitHub and Jenkins
- DevOps through the GCP, Kubernetes, and Docker
- Database and entity management through Doctrine ORM

## Aberystwyth University 2017–2021

#### **University Tutor**

Tutored Computer Science university students in a variety of different computer science contexts.

#### Responsibilities:

- Running workshops, lectures, and tuition groups with undergraduate students
- Hosting advisory sessions to help students through a wide range of problems
- One-to-one teaching
- Grading and supplying feedback to assignments and coursework

## Lexis Nexis Risk Solutions

May - Dec 2016

#### PHP Software Engineer

Operated with a team of developers/testers to implement industry quality software through a Zend Framework. Responsible for pushing code to a Jenkins CI server, and ensuring code quality through custom codesniffers and unit/integration tests.

#### Responsibilities:

- Working in an Agile team delivering user stories through sprints
- Peer reviewing code
- Developing features involving both front-end and back-end aspects
- Writing PHPUnit tests

## Education

## Aberystwyth University 2017–2021

## PhD Topological Mapping Swarm Robotics

Worked on novel solutions for the topological multi-agent SLAM problem, using a swarm of agents to map out an environment. Involved with writing ROS modules to achieve challenging tasks in languages such as C++, Java, and Python.

#### Responsibilities:

- Developing a simulator for robotic operations
- Innovating novel ideas to solve challenging problems
- Communicating technical work for both short term and long term reports
- Self managing time and effort

## Aberystwyth University 2014–2016

#### **BSc Computer Science**

During the degree, a wide range of technologies were studied which are still utilised today.

## Modules:

- Web programming
- Java, C, and C++ programming paradigms
- Software development lifecycle
- Human computer interface and human computer interaction
- Agile methodologies
- Advanced computer graphics
- Ubiquitous computing
- Space robotics
- Professional issues in the computing industry

## Personal Details

- Enthusiast that enjoys experimenting with new and emerging technologies with a keen interested eye on the future of the industry.
- Experience with using ROS to control robots in simulation and real world application.
- Interests include rugby, personal fitness, and video games.
- Friendly and approachable personality, with confidence to ask questions and collaborate with others.
- Full UK driving licence.